A Guide to the Rockingham County Moonshine Oral Histories: SdArch 33
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Rockingham County Moonshine Oral Histories
2009-2010
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Tiffany, Cole
SdArch 33
244
.01 cubic feet; 2 cd-rs
Rockingham County Moonshine Oral Histories, 2009-2010, is comprised of recorded interviews with five individuals who discuss moonshining in the Shenandoah Valley.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to oral histories is governed by agreements with the interviewees. Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Items were donated by Tiffany Cole on July 15, 2010.
Bio/Historical Note
Tiffany Cole completed a masters thesis titled, "Moonshining in Rockingham County: a case study in oral traditions and folkways," in 2010, in fulfillment of a Masters in History at James Madison University. The paper explores the history of moonshining in the Shenandoah Valley, starting in the mid-1700s, and uses oral histories to examine ways local residents perceive moonshiners, and how moonshiners perceive themselves.
Scope and Content
Rockingham County Moonshine Oral Histories, 2009-2010 is comprised of recorded interviews with five individuals who discuss moonshining in the Shenandoah Valley. Individuals interviewed by Cole are descendants of people who made or sold moonshine in the Shenandoah Valley, and discuss their memories of the moonshine business, and family stories that were passed down about the practice.
Arrangement
The interviews are arranged chronologically, by the date of the interview.
Bibliography
Cole, Tiffany W., "Moonshining in Rockingham County: A case study on oral traditions and folkways" (2010). Masters Theses. 406.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Mountain people -- Virginia -- Shenandoah National Park -- Social life and customs; Mountain life -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Folklore -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Storytelling -- Virginia; Traditional medicine -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Superstition -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Superstition -- Virginia -- History; Rockingham County (Va.) -- History; Shenandoah National Park (Va.) -- History, Local
Genre and Form Terms:
oral histories (literary works)
- 33-1: Peggy Shifflett, interviewed by Tiffany Cole, August 7, 2009
  - Original cd (Box 1, Cd-r SA033-OP-001)
- 33-2: Desmond Dove, interviewed by Tiffany Cole, August 8, 2009
  - Original cd (Box 1, Cd-r SA033-OP-002)
- 33-2: Chris Mathias, interviewed by Tiffany Cole, August 27, 2009
  - Original cd (Box 1, Cd-r SA033-OP-002)
- Pat Ritchie, interviewed by Tiffany Cole, November 19, 2009
  - Original cd (Box 1, Cd-r SA033-OP-002)
- Tammy Losh, interviewed by Tiffany Cole, January 5, 2010
  - Original cd (Box 1, Cd-r SA033-OP-002)